Wilfred Lewis

Construction
Carpenter/Project
Manager

Contact

Address

Brooklyn, NY, 11236

Phone

(347) 398-2011

E-mail

willie1963w@gmail.com

Skills

Excellent Communication

Excellent

Problem-Solving

Excellent

Project planning and development

Excellent

Drywalling

Excellent

Blueprint reading

Excellent

Project Management

Excellent

Physical stamina

Excellent

I'm a highly motivated carpenter foreman promoting exemplary job site supervision, communication and time management skills.

Knowledgeable in safety processes, regulations and blueprint reading. I been in the construction industry over 40 years with proven unique skills, great leadership and positive attitude. My objective is to apply my experience to benefit this organization.

Work History

2019-03 -2022-08

Carpenter Foreman

Abco Drywalls & Ceilings , New York , NY

- Coordinated movement of materials and equipment to job sites, verifying supply readiness prior to project start.
- Observed all OSHA and corporate safety regulations and procedures to prevent mishaps and injuries on job sites.
- Inspected work performed by carpentry crews to check completion of job specifications.
- Kept accurate records of materials used, employee timesheets, client issues and accident reports.

2010-11 -2019-06

Project Manager

Key Construction, Brooklyn, NY

 Developed and initiated projects, managed costs and monitored performance.

2008-08 -2010-10

Foreman

Innovative Construction, Inc., NY

- Handled issues with relative ease by implementing best practices and applying critical thinking skills to find best solutions.
- Checked equipment to determine if maintenance was required.
- Reworked positions and workflow based on individual abilities and production targets.
- Interacted with employees to demonstrate high standards and mitigate issues effectively.

1989-12 -2008-02

Project Manager

Key Construction, Brooklyn, NY

Residential construction

Excellent

Basic plumbing knowledge

Excellent

Hand and power tools

Excellent

Custom cabinetry expert

Excellent

Framing knowledge

Excellent

OSHA regulations

Excellent

Dependable and Responsible

Excellent

Trim work

Excellent

- Developed and initiated projects, managed costs and monitored performance.
- Met project deadlines without sacrificing build quality or workplace safety.
- Facilitated communication between internal personnel, contractors and vendors for project cohesion.
- Maintained relationships with material vendors to lower costs and diversify capabilities.

1982-03 -1989-11

Carpenter

Key Construction, Brooklyn , NY

- Checked measurements and completed accurate cuts to prevent materials waste and maintain cost controls.
- Planned and executed work with proper tools and materials to maximize productivity.
- Organized project work by reading blueprints and assessing job specifications to determine optimal plans.
- Completed installations of building structures, trim, flooring and cabinetry.

Education

1975-09 -1979-06

High School Diploma

Wesley College - Grenada